Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI - Photographs
  - Subseries A. Berens River Ojibwa Album, 1930s; Copy: 338 photos
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen, 'Fair Wind' [(1841?-1944) -- J. Brown], [1930s] [1938?]; A204
      p. 96 in Hallowell's Berens River Album. Naamiwan (John) Owen, Medicine man and leader of ceremonies in Pauingassi, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A205, A206, A207, F59, F142
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen, 'Fair Wind' [(1841?-1944) -- J. Brown], [1930s] [1938?]; A205
      Naamiwan (John) Owen, Medicine man and leader of ceremonies in Pauingassi, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A204, A206, A207, F59, F142
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen, 'Fair Wind' [(1841?-1944) -- J. Brown], [1930s] [1938?]; A206
      Naamiwan (John) Owen, Medicine man and leader of ceremonies in Pauingassi, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A204, A205, A207, F59, F142
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen, 'Fair Wind' [(1841?-1944) -- J. Brown], [1930s] [1938?]; A207
      Naamiwan (John) Owen, Medicine man and leader of ceremonies in Pauingassi, Manitoba, Canada. [Holding snowy owl or swan wing -- J. Brown 2/96]. See also: A204, A205, A206, F59, F142
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen, [1930s] [1938?]; A208
      p. 98 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Aankus (Angus) Owen, elderst son fo Naamiwan, followed his father in leading the Pauingassi ceremonies and also the shaking tent. See also A210, A 211.
      Owen, Aankus, (Angus); Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen & wife Miskwa'o (Red Bird), 1933; A209
      Aankus and Miskwa'o Owen. Aankus was a conjurer and the son of Naamiwan (John) Owen. This couple raised Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen. His mother died when he was a baby and as his mother's sister, Miskwa'o looked after him. See also: A208, A210, A211, F63, F64.
      Owen, Angus; Owen, Miskwa'o, (Red Bird); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen & wife Miskwa'o (Red Bird), [1930s] [1938?]; A210
      Aankus and Miskwa'o Owen. Aankus was a conjurer and the son of Naamiwan (John) Owen. This couple raised Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen. His mother died when he was a baby and as his mother's sister, Miskwa'o looked after him. See also: A209, A211, F63, F64
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen & wife Miskwa'o (Red Bird), [1930s] [1938?]; A211
      p. 99 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Aankus and Miskwa'o Owen. Aankus was a conjurer and the son of Naamiwan (John) Owen. This couple raised Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen. His mother died when he was a baby and as his mother's sister, Miskwa'o looked after him. See also: A209, A210, F63, F64
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Niizhiishaan (James Bearhair) Owen, [1930s]; A212
      p. 100 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Nizhishaan (James Bearhair) Owen (aka. Maahkikaat?). Father of Spoot Owen. See also: A213, F154, F163
      Owen, Niizhishaan, (James Bearhair); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Niizhiishaan, (James Bearhair) Owen & family, [1930s] [1938?]; A213
      Niizhiishaan (James Bearhair) Owen (Mahkikaat), wife and seven children. p. 100 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: A212, F154, F163
      Owen, Niizhishaan, (James Bearhair); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Waanachense (Alex) Owen Sr., his wife Kaapech & their children, 1933; A214
      Waanachense (Alex) Owen and his (2nd) wife, Kaapech, and their three daughters. P. 101 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: A215, F143?
      Owen, Kaapech; Owen, Waanachense, (Alex); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Waanachense (Alex) Owen Sr., his wife Kaapech & their children, [1940?]; A215
      Waanachense (Alex) Owen and his (2nd) wife, Kaapech, and their three daughters. P. 101 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: F143, [A214?]
      Owen, Kaapech; Owen, Wechaanimaash, (James); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wechanimaash (James) Owen, [1930s] [1938?]; A216
      Wechanimaash, sone of Naamiwan (John) Owen. p. 102 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: A220, A221, A222, F161
      Owen, Wechaanimaash, (James); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, ceremonial frame with boughs, [1930s]; A217
      Ceremonial frame and boughs.
      Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Pauingassi, view of lake shore with offering, [1930s]; A218
    - Berens River rapids with canoes and men shifting packs, [1930s]; A219
      Berens River rapids with canoes and men shifting packs.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wechanimaash (James) Owen, 1933; A220
      Wechanimaash (James) Owen. in front of log house at Pauingassi. See also: A216, A221, A222, F161
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wechanimaash (James) Owen & family, 1933; A221
      Wechanimaash (James) Owen and his wife Maa'aanjosh (Lillian) Owen and their five children. p. 103 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: A216, A220, A222, F161
      Owen, Wechaanimaash, (James); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wechanimaash (James) Owen & family, [1940?]; A222
      p. 103
      See also: A216, A220, A221, F161
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wewaant & family, 1933; A223
      Wewaant, his wife, and their family, seven children. p. 104 o Hallowell's Berens River Album.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Meme (or Osiyensima?) & Ahkaakochiis (Shawtail) Owen, 1933; A224
      Ahkaakochiis and his son, Meme or Osiyensima. p. 104 of Hallowell's Bernes River Album.
      Owen, Ahkaakochiis, (Shawtail); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Sarah Crow, wife of Joseph Crow and two children, 1933; A225
      Sarah Crow, wife of A'ase (Joseph) Crow with two children, small boy and older girl. p. 104 of Hallowell Berens River Album.
    - Paddle wheel boat, Prince Albert (David N Winston ) on lake, [1930s] [1931?]; A226
      The "Prince Albert" operated by Robert R. Winston, Boom Drag. See also: A227
    - Paddle wheel boat, Prince Albert (David N Winston ) on lake, [1930s] [1931?]; A227
      The "Prince Albert" operated by Robert R. Winston, Boom Drag., [Fenges [?] Lumber Co., The Postman [?], Carrot & Sask. Rivers]. See also: A226
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Maadoz, wife and baby, [1930s] [1938?]; A228
      Maadoz, (William Owen, grandson of Naamiwin, son of James Owen), (also in apprentices photo) wife and baby in a tikanagan with a small drum and drumstick. p. 106 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: F144
      Owen, William F. W.; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Es (Jacob) Owen, wife & family, [1930s] [1938?]; A229
      Es (Jacob) Owen with his wife and his family, a boy, two girls and a baby. p. 106 of Hallowell's Berens River Album.
      Owen, Es, (Jacob); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Miskwadezii Oshkiishik (Moses) Owen, 1933; A230
      Miskwadezii Oshkiishik (Moses) Owen. p. 107 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: F57, F148
      Owen, Miskwadezii Oshkiishik, (Moses); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Odaab, "Everlasting woman", 1933; A231
      Odaab, 'Everlasting woman'. See also A200. p. 107 of Hallowell's Berens River Album.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wiisakejaak (William) & Maanaadis (Elizabeth) Pascal, 1933; A232
      Wiisakejaak (William) Pascal and his wife Maanaadiz (Elizabeth) ne Owen - only daughter of Naamiwan and Koowin. Parents of Alex Pascal. p. 108 of Hallowell's Berens River Album.
      Pascal, Maanaadis, (Elizabeth, ne Owen); Pascal, Wiisakejaak, (William); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Alex Pascal & family, 1933; A233
      p. 108 from Hallowells' Berens River Album. Alex Pascal (son of William and Elizabeth Pascal - Wiisakejaak and Maanadiz. [May be in A200 - possibly Jiibay in back row. M.Matthews 4/12]
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, family, 1933; A234
      p. 108 in Hallowell's Berens River Album. Man, woman and three kids. [Possibly Boozhi Pascal and his wife, Elizabeth. M.Matthews 4/12]
      Pascal, Boozhi, (Bouchey); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Gichi Moosonii -'Big Moose' (Chiip) Keeper, wife Waawaak and children, 1933; A235
      Gitchi Moosonii (Chiip) Keeper and his 2nd wife wife Waawaak and their three children. p. 109 of Hallowell's Berens River Album.
      Keeper, Gichi Moosonii, (Chiip); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Thompson Keeper & his family, 1933; A236
      p. 109 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Thompson Keeper and his family, wife, three girls, One boy and one toddler. Daughter on the right is Waagidiniigan, 'Sun breaking through dark clouds'. See A237.
      Keeper, Waagidiniigan; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Waagidiniigan, "Sun breaking through dark clouds", 1933; A237
      Waagidiniigan, "Sun breaking through dark clouds". p. 109 of Hallwoell's Berens River Album.
      Keeper, Waagidiniigan; Ojibwa Indians; Ojibwe people
    - Berens River between Pauingassi and Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A238
      "En route" -- "water lions"
    - Berens River between Pauingassi and Poplar Hill, site of old HBC post, [1930s]; A239
      "En route" -- Site of old H.B. Post near Kterbanga [?]
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill. Naamiwan (John Owen) dance pavillion, [1930s]; A240
      Encampment A at Poplar Hill from emcampment B p. 114. Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion)
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Abenaki language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill. Naamiwan (John Owen) dance pavillion, [1930s]; A241
      Shows Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion) p. 114
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill. Naamiwan (John Owen) dance pavillion, [1930s]; A242
      Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion) used for Naamiwan's dream drum and drummers including three nephews of Naamiwan, Omishoosh (James) Owen and his brothers, Gezhiiyash (John) Owen, and Joozhi (Joseph Owen) Moose who brought Naamiwan's drum to Poplar River in the early 1920s. The drum was used in the Boodaade or "Ghost (or Spirit of the Dead) Dance" that originated with a dream of Naamawin's. P. 114 of Hallowell's photo album. See also A241, A242, A243, A244, A245.
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill. Naamiwan (John Owen) dance pavillion, [1930s]; A243
      Niimi'idiiwigamig (dance pavilion) used for Naamiwan's dream drum. Drummers included three nephews of Naamiwan, Omishoosh (James) Owen and his brothers, Gezhiiyash (John) Owen, and Joozhi (Joseph Owen) Moose who brought Naamiwan's drum to Poplar River in the early 1920s. The drum was used in the Boodaade or "Ghost (or Spirit of the Dead) Dance" that originated with a dream of Naamawin's. P. 115 of Hallowell's photo album. See also A241, A242, A244, A245, F176.
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill., [1930s]; A244
      p. 115, Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion) used in Naamiwan's drum dance. AIH saw the dance here in 1932] -- J. Brown. See also A241, A242, A243, A245. F176?
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion and mythology; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A245
      p. 115, Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion) used in Naamiwan's drum dance. AIH saw the dance here in 1932] -- J. Brown See also: See also A241, A242, A243, A244, F176?
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A246
      Dream dance drum, drummers in Niimi'idiiwigami (dance pavillion) used by Naamiwan. See also A241, A242, A243, A244, A245.
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A247
      p. 116
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Chooshi, Chaap, & family, [1930s]; A248
      p. 117
      A Saulteaux family
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A249
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A250
      p. 118
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A251
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Chechaakamaash, [1930s]; A252
      Tetakanias
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A253
      p. 119
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A254
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, sagmlnaknepik, [1930s]; A255
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A256
      p. 120
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Pechech & Inkaat, [1930s]; A257
    - Ojibwa, [Poplar Hill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s] [1938?]; A258
      p. 121
    - Ojibwa, [Poplar Hill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, Inchesh, Inchooch & family, [1930s] [1938?]; A259
      p. 122
      See also: A260
    - Ojibwa, [Poplar Hill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s] [1938?]; A260
      See also: A259
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A261
      p. 123
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A262
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A263
      Encampment B p. 124
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A264
      Cemetery -- Encampment B p. 124
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A265
      p. 124
      Photographer: Steve Boggs
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Shoomesh & family, [1930s]; A266
      p. 125
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, [1930s]; A267
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Kiishikaate, [1930s]; A268
      moonlight p. 125
      Kiz gate
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A269
      Asagesis tent
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A270
      p. 128
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A271
      p. 129
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, Nisleka [sp?], [1930s]; A272
      The daughter of the chief of Pikangikum. One of the beauties of the Saulteaux, she is holding a baby board p. 129
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, Kwikwishii, [1930s]; A273
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, Ochak, [1930s]; A274
      p. 130
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A275
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [Helen (Mrs. Stanley Quill) & her aunt (cont'd)], [1930s]; A276
      Nicka
      [Ohkanchiish, daughter of Sakashki. They are stretching a hide.] -- J. Brown
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A277
      p. 131
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, Okwikisak, [1930s]; A278
      Tananimänok [sp?]
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A279
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, Ashakeshi, [1930s]; A280
      p. 132
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, [1930s]; A281
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, 1932; A282
      After-birth on a pole in the woods
      See also: A283
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, 1932; A283
      See also: A282
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, [1930s]; A284
      Bear snare
      See also: A285
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, [1930s]; A285
    - Ojibwa, Bwt. Grand Rapids & Pikangikum, [William Berens], [1932?]; A286
      p. 137
      [Bwt. Poplar Hill & Pikangikum. "Our grandfather's rock" with offerings. The stone is a shrine.] -- J. Brown*
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A287
      View of encampment A from encampment B
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A288
      View of encampment A from across the bay
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [Stanley Quill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A289
      See also: A290, A291, F58
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [Stanley Quill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A290
      See also: A289, A291, F58
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [Stanley Quill?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A291
      The oldest man at Pikangikum. He is over 80 and one of the heads of the medicine lodge.
      See also: A289, A290, F58
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A292
      p. 139
    - Ojibwa, [Pikangikum?] [Little Grand Rapdis?] -- J. Brown, 1930 - 1933; A293
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Joseph Crow & his first wife, [1930s]; A294
    - Ojibwa, [Pikangikum?]; Ojibwa dwelling -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A295
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A296
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Peter Quill & his son John, [1930s]; A297
      p. 141
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A298
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Abraham Keeper, Alex, Rebecca, James on the right, [1930s]; A299
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Pemosikissgok [sp?], [1930s]; A300
      p. 142
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Otter man & family Kakike (?) apanok on left, Chachaank, [1930s]; A301
      Ekintaan hiding, Minwewechiwanok (Johnny Turtle changed the above two around), Henry King, James in front
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A302
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A303
      p. 143
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A304
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A305
      [Encampment?] B
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown, [1930s]; A306
      [Keeper dwelling?] -- J. Brown 2/96
      See also: A307
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown, [1930s]; A307
      [Details of Keeper dwelling?] -- J. Brown 2/96
      See also: A306
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum (B), [1930s]; A308
      Abandoned camp (B) p. 144
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A309
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A310
      Fish drying rack -- Otter man camp
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A312
      Ponasking fish p. 146
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum (B), Tcabasigig gok [sp?], [1930s]; A313
      p. 146
      401
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Left to right: 1. 2. Charlotte Strang 3. 4. Booshe, [1930s]; A314
      5. Maanahkwens 6. Isabella Turtle pos. 232 Mänäkwes 235
      See also: F133
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A315
      p. 147
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Back row, left to right: 1. Anchikwanepik (Pasikwepis, [1930s]; A316
      Kitepew said), 2. Küsküskaa 3. 4. Ihkwet 5. Ochünükan 6. Kitepwe Johnny Turtle in front *
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A317
      Tyhe 1 -- fishes, marten, mink, etc.
      See also: A318, A319, A320, A321, F123, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A318
      See also: A317, A319, A320, A321, F123, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A319
      Tyhe 3 -- bear
      See also: A317, A318, A320, A321, F123, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A320
      Tyhe 2 -- [otter, beaver]
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A321, F123, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls [Pikangikum?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [1930s]; A321
      Tyhe 2 -- otter, beaver
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A320, F123, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A322
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A323
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A324
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A325
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A326
      Smooth rock
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A327
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A328
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A329
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A330
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A331
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A332
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A333
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A334
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A335
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids?] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1940 [?]; A336
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [Antoine Bittern & family, married to Rosie Berens, William's, 1940 [?] [1952?] -- J. Brown 2/; A337
      Atione Bittern married Rosie Berens, William Berens' daughter -- J. Brown 12/92]
      See also: A20, A338, F50
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [Antoine Bittern & family, married to Rosie Berens, William's, 1940 [?] [1952?] -- J. Brown 2/96; A338
      [Atione Bittern married William Beren's daughter Rosie-- J. Brown 12/92]
      See also: A20, A337, F50
  - Subseries B. Lac du Flambeau Album, 1930s; Copy: 18 photos
    Contains photographs and postcards of individuals and buildings. Most of the images in this album are postcards, and thus, were not reprinted.
    Description of the reproduction photographs (.5 box); 18 images.
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B1
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B2
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B3
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B4
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B5
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B6
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B7
      - Ojibwa settlement, [1930s]
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B8
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B9
      - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B13
        - Joseph Negoni and Leonard Brown, [1930s]
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B10
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B11
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B12
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B14
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B15
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B16
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B17
    - Ojibwa, [Lac du Flambeau], [1930s]; B18
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; A311
      p. 145
  - Subseries C. Lake Winnipeg Album, 1930; Copy (82 photos
    Contains photographs of scenery, Ojibwa and Cree individuals, housing structures, and camps. Also includes images of Island Lake, Cross Lake, and Norway House (a Cree Settlement). Additional photographs from this area are in Subseries F.
    Description of the reproduction photographs (2 boxes); 82 images.
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], June 30, 1930; C1
      "En route" -- the "Keenora" in dock at Selkirk
    - [Ojibwa], [Berens River?], 1930 - 1933; C2
      Same as: A32
    - [Ojibwa?] [Cree?], [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C3
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Grand Rapids, 1930; C4
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Grand Rapids, 1930; C5
      Grand Rapids from the boat
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Grand Rapids, 1930; C6
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River?], 1930 - 1933; C7
      Same as: A31
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, [or] Grand Rapids, 1930; C8
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C9
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C10
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C11
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C12
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C13
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C14
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, [or] Grand Rapids, 1930; C15
    - Forestry Island, [1930?]; C16
    - [Norway House, Manitoba] -- J. Brown 2/96, 1930; C17
      [North end of Lake Winnipeg] -- J. Brown 2/96
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C18
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C19
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C20
      Little Playgreen Lake from Forestry Island
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; C21